<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AdventurOS - Blog</title>
    <description>AdventurOS is an 2D RPG adventure based game that is entirely auto-generated by the content (folders and files) of your computer.</description>
    <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com</link>
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Happy AdventurOS year!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Adventurers, we usually don’t detach from reality as a continuum of time, but we cannot help to feel very excited to welcome 2017, the year of AdventurOS, when the first playable version will be available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been tough and a hell of a learning experience, still with challenges to overcome and a lot of features that we would l love to fit in the first version so we are going to keep working as hard as possible to get them ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it is usual for the development of any game there have been adjustments of features and ideas for a better fit in gameplay and feel of the game, so we will also update you guys on how the game looks and feels like today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the fundamental key points of the game has changed, and the original concept has been kept or even improved.&lt;br /&gt;We consider every change implemented as totally worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AdventurOS is our shared, nearly accomplished New Year’s resolution, and here’s some more open thoughts on last year and resolutions for the next, with love, by the team members:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Andre:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“2016 is over. It happened so fast! With the demands of everyday life plus office work (In Tokyo, this is not to be underestimated) I wasn't able to stay up to my potential.&lt;br /&gt;
I would like to focus on making a day for discovery and creativity out of every day, instead of a simple day of obligations and responsibilities, unleashing the creative energy that is boiling inside of me and crying out to get to the outside world.&lt;br /&gt;
With my creative self being so hungry, 2017 presents itself as a great opportunity, a delicious feast that is about to be served.&lt;br /&gt;
In short, my goal is to close the beginning of this cycle with an explosion of color and sounds. Everything learned will not be in vain. I look forward to starting the year!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lorena:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I never believed in calendars but I can’t wait to AdventurOS year!
Besides our upcoming title, I can’t wait to finally going 100% vegan, making it to the Polar Circle and overcoming my horrid, vicious blogging shyness so that I can finally post all the  thoughts and rants that are piling up in the dusty drawer.&lt;br /&gt;
I guess I also have a soon-to-be-failed resolution which is rescuing less animals so that maybe I can keep a tiny part of my mental sanity intact (like there’s any left…)&lt;br /&gt;
But forget that one cause it’s not gonna happen! The boys know it well.&lt;br /&gt;
Seeing the team reunite is another wish for this year, so let's make it happen!&lt;br /&gt;
Happy new year everyone!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Emilio:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was a long and hard year to overcome but we are finally there. &lt;br /&gt;
Since I started working on videogames, my way of thinking about them changed drastically, so my new year's top resolution is to reflect that in the way I continue to develop them, that, and also accepting my path as a computer guy. They say I'm even good at it, so… maybe I can move on and finally drop the rock star career thing! Not the professional path to pursue but I will still have it close to my heart. At least our games' soundtracks will always have a part of me in them. Have a great 2017 guys!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1483148843.gif&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; image-rendering: pixelated;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for being part of the AdventurOS family and have the greatest start of the year. We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-12-30T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/12/30/happy-adventuros-year.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/12/30/happy-adventuros-year.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Easy to say, hard to implement</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When you start the creative process it is all fun and games.
At least until you see how hard to implement those &quot;It'll be cool&quot; ideas are.&lt;br /&gt;
In development, things get complicated really fast. We have learned it the hard way. &lt;br /&gt;
A good example of this is something that goes unnoticed for most: the “inventory system”.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very simple to write &quot;inventory system&quot; on a text note without really understanding how much work it takes to make it materialise, let alone achieving the desired balance.&lt;br /&gt;
Once in touch with reality and in order to simplify this process we made a couple of algorithms that help us speed up the process and balance the different sets of items like weapons or potions through automated calculation. This will be re-balanced afterwards with testing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drop rate and the price will also be calculated depending on the stats value of the items. This way we can adjust the pros and cons and they will stay balanced in relation to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you have a screenshot of how this looks in the rough for now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1473468213.jpg&quot; /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see this properties when you hover the items to see if you are able to use them. &lt;br /&gt;
We also added some visual aids under the inventory slots to display the stats affected by the items equipped. &lt;br /&gt;
Red means a decrease and green means an upgrade on your current stats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We've been neglecting updates, but never AdventurOS' development. &lt;br /&gt;
Things got boring and most work is repetitive, but this is about to get exciting again.&lt;br /&gt;
For anything we have not written about, please feel free to write us on twitter, facebook, steam or the comment section!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-09-09T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/09/09/easy-to-say-hard-to-implement.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/09/09/easy-to-say-hard-to-implement.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Let's Talk About Progress</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1468849371.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello dear Adventurers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we come with a special update that covers the development status from all the different fronts of the game, each and every one of them being aspects of it we are very much invested in, and that we wish to be fully satisfied with before presenting it to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We divided it into sections so you get a better picture of how much has been done and what to expect for the first playable version. So, here we go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Art&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The items are all ready. Menus? Check! Characters, npcs and mobs are ready to rock. The particles are looking amazing. The music and other assets are also good to go.&lt;br /&gt;
We've now finished the bosses and environments for the first release, and they will increase in number in later versions.&lt;br /&gt;
Of course we keep future expansions in mind for which we only have drafts but no actual graphics yet, but in general the graphic aspect of the first AdventurOS version is ready to shine bright, with just a few little exceptions here and there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some attack and other “in between” animations will be added to the mobs in time.&lt;br /&gt;
Some of them already have this, but we will keep making them all look even more alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Audio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An awesome soundtrack is already rocking our long dev hours, but the last step in development will be implementing sound to the game itself.&lt;br /&gt;
Since we are using the terrible, terrible game maker, we decided not to import the audio files until the end to reduce loading time while testing.&lt;br /&gt;
We have most of the SFX ready, minus perhaps a few charming sounds to add to our enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Game Menu&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The menu is finished as stated above, although there is this one section that will not be open to the public until after the release.&lt;br /&gt;
We don't consider it to be relevant for now. We want to focus on the main game and add it later as promised to our backers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Items&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the items that are to be included on the first public version of the game are ready.
We have a wide variety of swords, spears, shields and all the other necessary equipment for your player.&lt;br /&gt;
The sprites are all ready for action, but we still need to pour a lot of hours into adding and adjusting the different stats of all the items.&lt;br /&gt;
Potions also need some extra work. For now every item is being cataloged with a set of general properties shared by all of them.&lt;br /&gt;
Our idea is for items to eventually get more interesting and significative effects and uses when equipped or consumed, such as glow, auras and other ideas that sound and will hopefully look great but are still not in development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Monsters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we were initially planning on creating a (perhaps unrealistic) amount of different monster behaviors. This is an area that we are actively developing right now. Unfortunately, the boss fights will have to be delayed and be added in an update after the initial beta release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;NPCS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have implemented 8 types of reasonably functional NPCS.&lt;br /&gt;
We still need to generate the NPCS that will give you quests. A lot more work needs to be invested in this area, it goes hand in hand with the monsters since both are based off your files and the development process is similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Quests&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic functionality of quests is working. You can take, locate, and complete quests.&lt;br /&gt;
We also have a long list of different kinds of missions to add but we still need to merge both worlds. After this and the usual testing, there will be a lot of things to do while you are fighting enemies and discovering the secret life of your files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Character skills and abilities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skills and abilities of the main character are half way done. We have some of the abilities that facilitate movement on the map, and some magic skills. The last ones on the progression tree have to be developed as well as the overall testing and balancing of the damage/mana cost, all of them also tested within the gameflow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Other areas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of areas that are not that easy to catalog or are too big to explain.&lt;br /&gt;
We wanted to make this article to let you know how the game is evolving and of course we can answer any further questions in the comment section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We understand that it has been a long time since we started this adventure together. We apologize for the delay and we promise it will all be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-07-18T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/07/18/lets-talk-about-progress.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/07/18/lets-talk-about-progress.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Inside the enemy’s brain</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1464227745.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello there dear Adventurers!&lt;br /&gt;
Special kudos to our newsletter&amp;rsquo;s subscribers! You will definitely be the first ones to read the blog entry, so welcome! If you wish to subscribe but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, just &lt;a href=&quot;http://eepurl.com/b3dF7b&quot;&gt;CLICK HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today we bring you a very interesting topic: The enemies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The monsters are crucial for AdventurOS to be the fun game it is.&lt;br /&gt;
Getting your own files to chase you around is really cool! However, adjustments have had to be made along the development process.&lt;br /&gt;
When we started coding the artificial intelligence of the enemies, we made them pretty good at killing you. They could see where you were and where you were running to, plus they dodged your attacks.&lt;br /&gt;
After play testing a little bit we realised they were out of proportion. If you analyze the monsters in similar titles, you will notice that those monsters follow patterns.&lt;br /&gt;
You hardly ever come across a game where enemies show diverse ways to approach you. Instead, they repeat patterns and therefore become predictable. Why? Because, when well calibrated, getting to know how to defeat predictable enemies is very entertaining.&lt;br /&gt;
And that is how we noticed AdventurOS needed to undergo such calibration too.&lt;br /&gt;
You need gracefully choreographed actions to defeat your enemies, so knowing how they will behave is the most important skill to master if you wish to succeed.&lt;br /&gt;
Too effective monsters can be very frustrating, so in order to make the game fairer to the player, we basically started from scratch and redesigned the different patterns.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There are two main kinds of enemies in AdventurOS, the ones who can fly and the ones who can&amp;#39;t.&lt;br /&gt;
Flying monsters can be tricky to implement sometimes. They are pretty simple to code but at the same time it is not easy to find ways in which flying monsters can make navigating harder, which is the usual goal of flying enemies in levels.&lt;br /&gt;
On the other hand, we have the walking monsters which are there to challenge your skills and test your abilities. They are harder to defeat and always ready to surprise you. But in AdventurOS you can bend the rules and use the elements in your favor to turn those hard fights into an easier task. After all, you can easily extinguish a fire with water, can&amp;rsquo;t you?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1464227862.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1464227944.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for all the positive feedback we keep receiving. Please feel free to send those aspects of the game you are curious about, and we will do our best to give you a closer look into it through the gates of the amazing AdventurOS castle.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-05-25T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/05/25/inside-the-enemys-brain.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/05/25/inside-the-enemys-brain.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Behind The Design Process of AdventurOS</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello there!&lt;br /&gt;
We know it has been a long time, and we thank you all for your kind messages of support!&lt;br /&gt;
We would like to encourage all of you guys to send us your inquiries because we think you deserve our feedback and we really want to be there for you.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today we want to tell you a little bit more about what&amp;#39;s behind the design process of AdventurOS. The game.&lt;br /&gt;
When we started flirting with the idea of creating a world out of each computer&amp;#39;s files and folders, we encountered a lot of problems and exciting riddles to solve (to say the least!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;margin-right: 20px; max-width: 200px; display:inline-block; float:left;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1462843259.jpg&quot; /&gt;A classic one is the zip files being interpreted as chests. When you have a game in mind that enables the player to create the rooms, you have to make sure the design includes measures to avoid cheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to fix the problem of the player having the chance of creating unlimited chests, what we did was simple: We added a key for each chest you want to open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes getting keys necessary before being able to open chests. And, how do you get those keys?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keys are only earned by killing files, so if you want to open all the chests in that chamber that you just smartly created, you have a long way ahead of you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue has to do with the room generation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is very hard to create a procedural world that is connected so that the player progresses, while you must also add obstacles to block access to certain rooms so that the game still makes sense. If that makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you already know, metroidvania games give you abilities that invite you to re-explore areas that you have already visited in order to unlock extra content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In AdventurOS you will need to get this special abilities by earning Adventure Points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several ways of bypassing the special barriers created for you to overcome, and by exploring you will acquire the skills needed for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get Adventure Points by visiting new areas or cleaning rooms in the castle or by finishing quests given to you by friendly NPCs. Long story short, the more adventurous you are, the more Adventure Points you can earn!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has improved the pacing of the game. You will keep discovering when you are able to face each new challenge ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of ideas that we thought were amazing turned out to be &amp;quot;not so good&amp;quot; once the prototype began to be playable, but the iteration process is making them all fit in place to ensure that the game will turn out to be fun and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;max-width:100%;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1462843170.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a long and painful process that taught us many things, what not to do among them, but soon enough we will enter the &amp;ldquo;Now we are talking&amp;rdquo; era for our dear baby game AdventurOS, and we will be very excited to welcome you all to enjoy it with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading and we&amp;#39;ll keep you posted, promise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-05-09T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/05/09/behind-the-design-process-of-adventuros.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/05/09/behind-the-design-process-of-adventuros.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hola from the team :)</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Adventurers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ninety nine point nine percent of your messages are of pure support and full of words of encouragement. There are, however, a few exceptions that show understandable signs of impatience about our release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us give you some perspective on this: &lt;br /&gt;
As AdventurOS parents, we decided to do this, and we decided to do this well.
The game has never been cancelled, and it will never be. That is out of the question, so everybody relax.&lt;br /&gt;
This is a ship that's being tricky to drive but that is far from sinking.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We work on it daily since day one and we keep working very hard.
AdventurOS is a game that we stupid newbies thought would be a piece of cake but turned out to be a titanic project.
We are just a crew of three and our funding was encouraging but merely anecdotic, so we must keep a regular job each to stay alive. So that we can develop AdventurOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our baby game we have all turned our backs to many other life opportunities so that we can keep working on this and finally make it happen.
You have all probably read about all the bureaucratic issues we also had and still have, which just adds up to the pile of shit independent developers must go through.
But for every challenge that's put in our way we just say BRING IT ON! even louder than before and get immediately back to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just want to go through it as gracefully as possible, without stepping on any of our principles (after all, that's what having no boss should mean) and it turns out that, in the meantime, many ideas were implemented in the now enormous AdventurOS snowball, so the tiny indie game we advertised is going to come up as an out of proportion piece of gaming awesomeness. This means that we must apologize for our unrealistic deadline and consequent delay, but that after all you guys will eventually get a game that is worth much more than what you initially paid for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have discussed this before with our main backers and countless regular backers, and we all agree on a &quot;product over deadline&quot; approach.
By the way, thank you guys for walking this path alongside us!
We thank you for your patience and understanding of the full picture, and AdventurOS is going to be everyone's reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big hugs, we love you all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AdventurOS Team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-02-16T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/02/16/hola-from-the-team.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/02/16/hola-from-the-team.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Happy New Year!!!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! Our months working together in Tokyo were wonderful development-wise, but now it's time to part and be back to remote collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will miss each other very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should our passport country (Spain) be in a different phase, I think we'd all give settling here a shot. However, this country is far from being a self-employed or freelance-friendly one, and it is especially unadvised if you work in the software industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a chance that the strongest emergent party could change that in the long run, but it does not seem to be going to happen in the near future. Now Spain doesn't even have a government to begin with!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever happens, and wherever each of us chooses to spend 2016, we have just charged batteries together and are determined to take AdventurOS very far. We apologize again for the unrealistc deadline we once set, but it will all be worth it, for us and also for you guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have so far walked a path of exploration and discovery of our own profession, of the industry and all other (rather stupid) rules that may (and will!) apply. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for walking along with us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, if you are curious about what's lately on our desks, we can start by telling you how pleased we are to have replaced the Python indexer side with golang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the Story Mode took shape and we are loving it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development processes are usually surrounded by much secrecy, but this time we have cool footage to show you guys, and you can choose what to see next by leaving your suggestions in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8-YeCek865Y?rel=0&amp;amp;controls=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2016-01-01T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/01/01/happy-new-year.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2016/01/01/happy-new-year.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #18</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1446207276.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1446207251.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1446207237.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1446207216.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good morning, afternoon and evening, fellow Adventurers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We Evelend team are fully focused on work here in Tokyo. We are now reunited and able to share the same “office” and to finally work side by side after so much remote collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a having a very productive time here, but we have a limited number of months to spend together, so the goals are making the best out of it and pave the way for a smooth transition back to remote work when it’s time to part again. Sigh...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our latest work has been focused on the replacement of all the code in Python by code in Go (golang), because of Python’s limitations when it comes to distributing executables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially an issue for Windows users, given that OSX and Linux have it pre-installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Windudes messing with us again… but hey! a deal is a deal and this game is going to be available to all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those kind Indiegogo contributors who chose the highest perks should have received an email from us about displaying their info in AdventurOS credits, so if you are one of those contributors but you have not received the email, please get in touch with us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now a thank you note to all our supporters.Big and small. Pioneer and late additions. Thank you so much. This is all possible thanks to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wish you a wonderful gaming time, see you soon for more updates about AdventurOS game! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-11-06T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/11/06/development-update-18.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/11/06/development-update-18.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>One for all, and all for one!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1442601064.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; style=&quot;float:left; margin:20px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello dear friends,&lt;br /&gt;
This letter will disappoint many, but not those you are thinking. This update of ours will disappoint the ones systematically mentioning, almost seeming to wish, our development interruption. To all those, we are sorry. Brace yourselves. AdventurOS is coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, however, not the announcement of its release, but it is getting closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;#39;t know, AdventurOS team went to hell and back to make this possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had all sorts of administrative problems and we could not fix them all yet. Not even by moving to other countries and continents with the sole purpose of paperwork for release.&lt;br /&gt;
Since ours was already a team of globetrotters, we just tried to go through it all as gracefully as possible, and even though we needed other jobs to keep us going, AdventurOS development has, not a single day, become the one on the side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This world is definitely not made for independent authors, but we know exactly in which way we want this handled, we know we have the right to it and the ability to do it without intermediaries, and we will not rest until we get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AdventurOS will be out before we reach our actual goal (the Steam release) because our bureaucratic delay forced us to make Steam also wait.&lt;br /&gt;
We then pushed &amp;quot;hype and exposition theories&amp;quot; away and decided to launch AdventurOS independently on our site as soon as we are happy with it, and save our spot on Steam for later.&lt;br /&gt;
This way we will give you access as soon as possible, regardless of when we get the chance to peak in our sales through bigger platforms. If that is ever happening.&lt;br /&gt;
Revenue has become secondary in our struggle to stay independent and do things our way, paving the way to others who might want to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we figure this out ourselves, we will undoubtedly put all the info out there for those considering joining the industry, but first we need to learn. We hope all our war scars are of service to others some time in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having to postpone our initial, naive deadline, and getting such avalanche of words and gestures of support from the community definitely helped us staying strong, and believe us, we are soon paying you guys back by modestly launching on our site, with you in mind instead of our own sales strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick note to our kind contributors with highest donations, please remember your version of AdventurOS will always keep updating on Dropbox. Feel free to get in touch if you have any questions or technical issues, and enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AdventurOS development will most probably speed up from today.&lt;br /&gt;
We all finally made it to Tokyo, and we have not met yet, but we will very soon reunite and we&amp;#39;ll finally work in the same room again. We can&amp;#39;t wait!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any of you currently staying in Tokyo, we will be happy to meet up, preferably off the beaten track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots of dev love from Japan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evelend Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1442601306.png&quot; style=&quot;height:50px; margin:0 auto; width:78px&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-09-18T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/09/18/one-for-all-and-all-for-one.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/09/18/one-for-all-and-all-for-one.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Once upon a time...</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We know you have been wondering about the plot. Here's finally an article telling a bit about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/gTfSV8e.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story begins with your recently installed convoy arriving into the castle.
This happens to take place in the middle of a crisis within its walls, which seem to have gone through some kind of curse.
The castle has turned very dangerous, full of creatures and traps, and there is no room for any newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/dwoBjwX.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your group offers help “cleaning up” the castle in exchange for shelter.
The rules state that “Everyone and everything the Architect lets in, shall stay, unless the Architect, and no one else, decides otherwise” This is why these people eventually accept your help, but not without you having to struggle first with the long-established policies and protocols of the castle and some of the most powerful individuals in it, who seem to be rather eager to kick you out of there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/1g3dxDG.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will not be long until you end up in the epicentre of an internal dispute which threatens to make the whole place fall apart. It will be your mission to unravel the truth behind the conspiracy and to save the filers, (the citizens), from the cruel destiny awaiting in the deep dark corners of the castle, all under the watchful eye of the Architect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the nature of the curse? Who does the whole situation benefits and why? What's on stake? Are you ready? &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-07-16T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/07/16/once-upon-a-time.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/07/16/once-upon-a-time.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #17</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Adventurers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our work on AdventurOS continues! You know the challenges we are going through, both of bureaucratic and technical natures, but rest assured that when AdventurOS goes public, everything will have been worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;normal&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/RWuEL5A.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Aq3jHic.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/fHVTSY9.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/kKlCevk.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/MJXphyO.gif&quot; class=&quot;normal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must all have noticed how much we have come to hate Game Maker, and it is not getting any better. &lt;br /&gt;
Many of you have suggested switching to a new framework, which of course makes sense, but, let's save you the technicalities here, it is just too late for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point we are eager to release the first version of the awesome AdventurOS, and this will be a 2D version, which is still awesome thanks to André's art, does not compromise the game at all, and has actually a much better quality than we expected. The 3D version will be implemented as soon as its performance reaches our expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feature after feature, the game gets more complete and nicer to play. We have lately been doing many implementations, like the directory system (where to put all pieces of the great AdventurOS puzzle together), and also aspects of the inventory, quests, combat and physics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/QvOd88b.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also been merging the room generator with the new engine, and working on the upcoming Challenge Mode. The result will not deceive you guys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/80E6Nhu.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for your constant support. We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-06-17T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/06/17/development-update-17.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/06/17/development-update-17.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #16</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s been a long time since we started working on AdventurOS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Before we even made public the concept, it came to life as a Pygame project.&lt;br /&gt;
As the project grew bigger, we started adding more content to the little engine and not much later it obviously started to slow down.&lt;br /&gt;
Most of you might already know Python/Pygame is not very efficient when it comes to games. That is why we decided to develop it using Game Maker when we launched the indiegogo campaign. We were all familiar with the tool and it was powerful enough to perform the way we had in mind.&lt;br /&gt;
By that moment we were using Game Maker 8, so part of the money of the crowdfunding went towards an upgrade of our license to GM:Studio.&lt;br /&gt;
The new version of the program, developed by Yoyo Games, was going to allow us to develop a cross platform game. &amp;quot;Code once, run everywhere&amp;quot;, they said.&lt;br /&gt;
But reality is when we started coding the nightmare began. &amp;quot;Code once, suck everywhere&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/CGrlzMo.png&quot; style=&quot;height:336px; width:726px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;After the fresh installation we noticed several changes in the software.&lt;br /&gt;
Some were good, some were bad and some were just TERRIBLE.&lt;br /&gt;
AdventurOS&amp;#39; key feature is precisely the indexing of files and folders to generate the levels, monsters and adventures.&lt;br /&gt;
While game maker 8 was great at doing this, the newest version GM:S dramatically limited that to only ONE folder per operative system. Adventcalypse.&lt;br /&gt;
The documentation about it is very poor and there is no information to be found about OSX or Linux.&lt;br /&gt;
The program has a feature to add external libraries as a complement to the engine, but the only external libraries allowed are DLLs which of course don&amp;#39;t work on any other platform than Windows, so there was really nothing we could to to bypass this limitation.&lt;br /&gt;
After asking on forums and contacting Yoyogames itself, all we got was pretty much a &amp;nbsp;&amp;quot;Go f**k yourself&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/jpfkK9e.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/jpfkK9e.png&quot; style=&quot;height:336px; width:726px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;By the time we launched the project, the NSA scandal was all over the internet and &amp;nbsp;people were skeptical about us indexing their system.&lt;br /&gt;
This meant that using any kind of networking to bypass the limitations of the engine was out of the question.&lt;br /&gt;
We refused, and still refuse, to send any package containing the user private information, not even locally. So, there was only one solution left.&lt;br /&gt;
We had to create a parallel process with Python in order to gather the information needed and store it as a temporary file on the game&amp;#39;s directory.&lt;br /&gt;
Developing that is not as simple as it seems, specially when it is expected to work on all platforms. Right now the indexer is pretty awesome but it was one of the hardest challenges we had to face during the early development of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/lrctV9z.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/lrctV9z.png&quot; style=&quot;height:336px; width:726px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/IsdZnFs.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/IsdZnFs.png&quot; style=&quot;height:336px; width:726px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have always had modding support in mind.&lt;br /&gt;
We designed the source to include many modding capabilities so other people can do whatever they want with the core idea of using the computer as a procedural generator seed. But once again GM got on our way.&lt;br /&gt;
From the documentation: &amp;quot;These functions cannot be used any more due to changes in the underlying runner that GameMaker: Studio uses to generate the device specific packages making it impossible to generate objects, images or code &amp;quot;on the fly&amp;quot; as was done before.&amp;quot; This means that all the resources have to be implemented, added and coded from within the GM IDE itself, so there was no way for us to allow any kind of modding without giving away all the game&amp;#39;s source code. We are still looking into ways of doing this but we might have to wait a little bit longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/IaDaWw2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/IaDaWw2.png&quot; style=&quot;height:336px; width:726px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;As for the gameplay itself, we are in continuous iteration.&lt;br /&gt;
It feels and looks very good, and lately we have been increasing the speed and adding variety to the enemies&amp;#39; IA. The latest additions to the hero&amp;#39;s abilities are the bow and arrow, but there are still some other magic skills ready to be implemented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;We have long wanted to give you this insight on the overall development process of the game since day 1, because there have been so many ups and downs, so many challenges to overcome! We are determined to accomplish our vision and deliver the best AdventurOS we can craft. Thank you for being so awesome!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-05-14T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/05/14/development-update-16.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/05/14/development-update-16.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #15</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings Adventurers!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
First of all, thank you ever so much for your words and gestures of support.&lt;br /&gt;
You will very soon be playing the super awesome AdventurOS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today we are letting you look through a crack of our castle&amp;#39;s wall.&lt;br /&gt;
Here you have several gameplay gifs.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/cY4wrFC.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Among other elements, we are working on the environment, the power-ups and the monsters, and the result is a much better flow when it comes to gameplay.&lt;br /&gt;
Also, many spells have already been implemented, and they look and feel great!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/kTKyZCu.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
There will be 7 different kinds of spells and 6 elements. These combined make a total of 42 spells to discover and master!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/qwCeNM9.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We are also proud to announce that once the game is out for sale, we will accept bitcoins, as so many of you wished and kindly requested.&lt;br /&gt;
It will be available as an alternative to the conventional currencies or services.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thank you so very much for your patience. We promise it will all be worth it!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-03-07T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/03/07/development-update-15.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/03/07/development-update-15.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #14</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy new year,&amp;nbsp;dear&amp;nbsp;Adventurers!&lt;br /&gt;
Last year was&amp;nbsp;full of adventures of all kinds for Evelend&amp;nbsp;team, and this one will be full of adventures for you!&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We are very&amp;nbsp;excited to see what lies&amp;nbsp;ahead for all of us immediately after&amp;nbsp;the last steps of our&amp;nbsp;bureaucratic&amp;nbsp;odyssey.&lt;br /&gt;
We wish we could have given&amp;nbsp;an earlier release, but the bright side is that AdventurOS becomes more and more&amp;nbsp;awesome every day in the meantime.&lt;br /&gt;
We want to&amp;nbsp;thank you all for&amp;nbsp;your messages and gestures of support and we are sure this will be worth all the efforts we put into it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today we are unfolding&amp;nbsp;AdventurOS development a&amp;nbsp;bit more for you.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Firstly, a&amp;nbsp;big improvement is taking place right now.&lt;br /&gt;
A second engine that will make mobs way more&amp;nbsp;dynamic and fun to play is being&amp;nbsp;implemented&amp;nbsp;and will be merged with the current one.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
We are focused&amp;nbsp;on providing&amp;nbsp;challenging&amp;nbsp;fights, a broader spectrum of&amp;nbsp;skills&amp;nbsp;and overall better&amp;nbsp;flow at our castle&amp;#39;s platforms,&amp;nbsp;making the experience&amp;nbsp;more&amp;nbsp;interesting and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294246.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294246.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, we have also improved a few other things, getting as a result:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
- A higher number of ways to personalize your monsters through&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;mob customization system.&lt;br /&gt;
- A more efficient&amp;nbsp;light engine that allows a better performance&lt;br /&gt;
- A&amp;nbsp;room interpreter that will make our castle&amp;nbsp;resemble our computer&amp;#39;s&amp;nbsp;visible folders and files&amp;nbsp;even better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some&amp;nbsp;upgrades wished by the team for&amp;nbsp;AdventurOS&amp;#39;&amp;nbsp;first release&amp;nbsp;are&amp;nbsp;yet to be crafted, but we are positive&amp;nbsp;the upcoming release will contain them all.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
All features in general&amp;nbsp;continue&amp;nbsp;according to plan&amp;nbsp;and we have an early version of the game running for the&amp;nbsp;contributors to our Indiegogo campaign with the highest perks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the administrative struggle for the sake of independence, we have also encountered a lot of technical challenges in the process of development,&amp;nbsp;but we guess that is something to expect when you work&amp;nbsp;on a product that is just unique.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We can&amp;#39;t wait to put it out there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like&amp;nbsp;to remind&amp;nbsp;everyone who has contributed to the Indiegogo campaign with the &amp;ldquo;CD&amp;rdquo; perk (and higher)&amp;nbsp;that you should have received a link to the OST via&amp;nbsp;e-mail.&lt;br /&gt;
In case&amp;nbsp;you did not receive&amp;nbsp;the e-mail, please feel free to get in touch!&lt;br /&gt;
Remember you can write to&amp;nbsp;info@evelend.com or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:evelend.info@gmail.com&quot;&gt;evelend.info@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and we will&amp;nbsp;deliver your perk right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AdventurOS is coming soon, our dear Adventurers! In the meantime,&amp;nbsp;here are some&amp;nbsp;recent screenshots you can check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294386.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294386.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294364.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294364.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294265.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294265.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294330.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1421294330.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for your support and happy gaming! We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2015-01-18T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/01/18/development-update-14.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2015/01/18/development-update-14.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>AdventurOST</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello again, our dear Adventurers!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Regardless of the bitter side of being indies and on our own, we are enjoying every second of development of the game, and you will very soon be playing it your way, at your very own realm.&lt;br /&gt;
We are a team of three grinches, all equally overwhelmed and confused by Christmas time. However, we know for many it does bring reunions and well deserved free time. Maybe you are up to some AdventurOS music?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
It is just about time for contributors with Floppy-disc perk or higher to enjoy the volume I of the amazing AdventurOS OST.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img style=&quot;display:block; margin: 0 auto;&quot; src=&quot;https://ci4.googleusercontent.com/proxy/dGBgr3II9kJXhmQZRJPHMoPVU67SMg4AVutpCYJd444EkNH4519AkmkdvGdMvf7MBOBILuCz5CvMr1gILVMMEtN5XwUJPdJzsqVFdr0UaZxa9q3O7Ii8I1HlFLORqfXhD25fbG3B4mQJ0kyef12CpMLWdHWunkbyPHQcQ8I=s0-d-e1-ft#https://gallery.mailchimp.com/2256b38cc5457252c5772cb4f/images/405f451e-de17-4bf6-9f75-cfcfed3624d7.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
You will receive an email with the download link. It contains nineteen beautifully composed songs by our inimitable artist Mr. Andr&amp;eacute; Mar&amp;iacute; Coppola. Check it out and&amp;hellip;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
ENJOY!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Thanks for your support! We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/12/18/adventurost.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/12/18/adventurost.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development update #13</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello dear Adventurers,&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
You might be aware of the latest news regarding our bureaucratic struggle. In case you are not, you might be interested in checking out &lt;a href=&quot;http://lorena.evelend.com/bureaucrazy/&quot;&gt;Lorena&amp;rsquo;s article&lt;/a&gt; on the subject.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Meanwhile, development keeps moving forward. And we can&amp;rsquo;t wait to the Early Access release!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today we will give you a glimpse of another small piece of AdventurOS: Lately we have focused on improving the skill menu, so here&amp;rsquo;s a teaser:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1412291168.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time you perform an adventure related action (Entering unopened rooms, completing a quest, defeating a boss) you will earn Adventure Points. With this special points you will be able to build your character skills the way you want them by selecting your chosen formula between magic upgrades, weapon skills or abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When creating your character a few basic skills will be already active so you can start with a preset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow this process and more through our site. You can stay updated by the team on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AdventurOSgame&quot;&gt;Twitter &lt;/a&gt;too.&lt;br /&gt;
We also had the nice surprise of finding out a kind active member of Reddit had long ago created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/adventuros/&quot;&gt;subreddit about AdventurOS&lt;/a&gt;, and he has gifted us the chance to participate and keep it up to date too. Check it out!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We would like to thank you once more for your support. We are flooded with kind words and warm wishes and we are doing our best to reach everyone back as soon as possible. Once again, thank you so much. We love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-10-02T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/10/02/development-update-13.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/10/02/development-update-13.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #12</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings, dear AdventurOS family!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1409778487.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We remain in that point where the job is done but the bureaucracy to release it is not yet sorted out.&lt;br /&gt;
The struggle is so big right now that all of us three have even moved in order to survive this delay.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
However, not everything is a struggle. AdventurOS still has most part of our energy and attention. This is good for us, as this is an awesome process that we are proud to be part of, and it is also good for you, because the first releasable version keeps getting better and better, so once it is out, it will be a much better product than we thought it would be at its Early Access stage.&lt;br /&gt;
The least we can do to make up for the delay is keeping up the constantly increasing game awesomeness.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Today we will tease you a little bit more by introducing you to your main character and its possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adventure will happen on your computer, but who is our protagonist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gameplay will follow the adventures of a simple file you will create.&lt;br /&gt;
You will be able to customize that file in many ways.&lt;br /&gt;
Gender, name, and hairstyle are attributes that other games already let you personalize when it comes to character customization, but what&amp;#39;s unique about AdventurOS is that since our hero is a file, you get to choose its extension.&lt;br /&gt;
What will that mean for your hero?&lt;br /&gt;
Each extension will have different attributes, skills and items to begin with, and the player will adopt the color of that extension&amp;rsquo;s family, having the other files with the same extension as allies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1409778030.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;p&gt;The high perk contributors to our Indiegogo campaign should expect an upgrade and more news very soon.&lt;br /&gt;
If you did not make it to the campaign but want to support AdventurOS development, you can pre-purchase &lt;a href=&quot;http://adventuros.evelend.com/store&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
We would also like to thank you all for your support messages. We like to personally write back to everyone and we do our best to not to delay much in our replies.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
So, as always, thank you all so much! We love you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-09-03T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/09/03/development-update-12.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/09/03/development-update-12.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #11</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately we introduced you to our &lt;a href=&quot;http://adventuros.evelend.com/blog/11&quot;&gt;monster creator&lt;/a&gt; and today we proudly present our latest addition to the AdventurOS toolset:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1407375397.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1407375731.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the item creator, you can create (no shit Sherlock) any item for the game and share it with your friends as well.&lt;br /&gt;
The price and drop rate of your item will be automatically generated based on its stats. By doing this we avoid disproportionate items on the game, so whatever you create will stay balanced with the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1407375417.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you very much for all the &lt;a href=&quot;http://adventuros.evelend.com/store/&quot;&gt;pre-purchases&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;
Oh! And&amp;hellip; on that note&amp;hellip; we have another surprise for you!&lt;br /&gt;
If you are one of the pre-purchasers, you have automatically entered a raffle.&lt;br /&gt;
The winner will be able to take part of the alpha testing too!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugs from the AdventurOS team!&lt;br /&gt;
- Andr&amp;eacute;, Emilio and Lorena &amp;hearts;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-08-06T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/08/06/development-update-11.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/08/06/development-update-11.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #10</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have so far talked about NPCs and monsters. Today we will focus on the sceneries where all the fun will take place!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1406194474.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environments will be created according to the type of file that is the most abundant within each folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we introduce you some of the environments you will find while exploring your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Library.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1406130635.png&quot; style=&quot;float:right;padding-left:10px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library is the centre where the scribes belong. It is where all information of the realm is gathered and kept for further study that will help you Adventurers in your quest.
Libraries will be generated in the folders containing a majority of text files and the like. They can be of varying sizes and number of floors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help the scribes broadening their knowledge by sharing your discoveries!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Temple.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1406130673.png&quot; style=&quot;float:left;padding-right:10px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The temples are a space for connection with the Great Architect. They will be generated out of folders containing a majority of audio files.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Music is considered the best way of spiritual expression in this realm.&lt;br /&gt;
The monks count on great power and influence, so having them as allies will certainly help you in you adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Village&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1406130661.png&quot; style=&quot;float:right;padding-left:10px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the villages is where you will find the highest density of population. Both the villages and the forests are generated out of the folders in which images are predominant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earn their support and make your own prestige increase by helping them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are only three examples among many other environments you will be able to explore.&lt;br /&gt;
Stay tuned for more teasers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love you all,&lt;br /&gt;
The team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-07-24T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/07/24/development-update-10.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/07/24/development-update-10.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Good news!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.evelend.com/images/1405171465.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello our dear Adventurers! We have a very good surprise for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have worked a lot to get where AdventurOS is today, and by now you already know how much we are struggling to finally put the result out there. For those who need to refresh it here is Lorena&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://lorena.evelend.com/indie-heaven-and-hell/&quot;&gt;illustrative article.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have contacted each and every one of you privately, but we would also like to publicly thank you for all the great feedback we got after sharing our experience, for the support letters and messages, for your tweets and retweets, for spreading the AdventurOS word and for all the different ways in which you have showed us your love. You are an amazing source of indie gaming awesomeness. Really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among all messages and within the whole development period we have got flooded with requests for us to accept donations and pre-purchases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the&lt;a href=&quot;https://sellfy.com/p/vL28/&quot;&gt; wallpapers pack&lt;/a&gt;, there has been no chance to purchase anything after AdventurOS Indiegogo campaign finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UNTIL NOW!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are reading this, then the AdventurOS &lt;a href=&quot;http://adventuros.evelend.com/store/&quot;&gt;pre-purchase option&lt;/a&gt; is already up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our delay, forced by our unexpected bureaucratic problems, motivated us to keep improving what was supposed to be the first Beta version, by adding more content. And more. And more! We are also polishing the existing features. And polishing... and polishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This train moves forward at full speed and the whole thing looks damn good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the first Early Access version is out, you will receive that one plus all further builds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only the few brave people who trusted us with contributions for the right perks on Indiegogo from the very beginning can enjoy the privilege of playing the latest alpha builds of the game before the early-access release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it won&amp;#39;t be long before all of you get the great looking AdventurOS Early Access that will soon see the light on Steam!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope we are properly reaching everyone and listening to all requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides everything explained above, and after many messages requesting the same, we have finally created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://adventuros.evelend.com/blog/feed/&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; for everyone to stay updated from now on through any chosen reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We feel utterly happy to see how AdventurOS concept, which we once wanted to bring to life out of pure creativity and passion, quickly becomes contagiously wished and supported by so many people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we are making it happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again for everything and let there be games!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love,&lt;br /&gt;
Evelend Team&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-07-14T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/07/14/good-news.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/07/14/good-news.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #9</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello once again for some refreshing news on AdventurOS development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/1gaYxXw.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people have asked us about the file extensions that might not be recognized by default in AdventurOS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the game encounters an extension that was not contemplated on our design, a random monster will spawn taking that extension's role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BUT, what if we do not want a random monster in one of our custom extensions? We have a way cooler option for you guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow us to introduce you to the Monster Creator!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/preview/monstereditor.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this simple program you will be able to create and edit monsters so they can be bound with any file extension you want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, let’s say we have a saved file called &quot;my_game.sav&quot; and we want AdventurOS to generate a fire monkey whenever we find any .sav file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/preview/firemonkey.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After creating this monster you will find it in game whenever you come across files with your chosen extension for that monster to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/preview/ingame.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An awesome feature of the Monster Creator is the possibility to share your monsters with other Adventurers if you wish to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also be able to download and use other people's creations with a simple url pasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/preview/import.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have some other teasers to give you today:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Meet the Mechanic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/93zGYuy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/oUSmQOH.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/kCj01ko.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mechanics&lt;/b&gt; (Created from shortcuts) Their mission will be protecting the links between rooms and managing all the portal system of the castle.&lt;br /&gt;
They will be the ones with tools such as locked doors or hyperlinks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Meet the Monk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/JDQP6gp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/jVeekmB.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Lhv9znO.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Monks&lt;/b&gt; (Created out of all kinds of audio files) Each audio file generates a monk plus a CD item.&lt;br /&gt;
When the item is given to a monk, it stays attached to the monk as the piece they will later interpret by turns, because, you know, that will be their thing.&lt;br /&gt;
We expect the monks to reproduce your audio files, but we cannot promise the will not include funny distortions too!&lt;br /&gt;
While the monks sing, you can receive useful temporary buffs such as increased experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will hopefully be sharing AdventurOS fun very soon. Meantime, we want to thank you all for all the great support we are receiving!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Cheers!&lt;br /&gt;
The team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-06-27T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/06/27/development-update-9.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/06/27/development-update-9.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #8</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We proudly introduce you to some of the characters that will make your journey easier in exchange for your fight against the curse.
The rooms in your castle are infected and must be cleaned.
Killing every monster in the area will make it clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/C01z7vj.png&quot; alt=&quot;room difference&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will not modify your files! Villagers and NPCs will spawn there, replacing the defeated monsters, as long as the file exists..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Meet the Stylist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/TgybudF.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/465fhxJ.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xfmJVPC.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To encounter a stylist you first have to clean a room with vector graphics. The quantity of files determines the quantity of the hairstyles and other customization options that are available. (Only 1 vector graphic will transform, the rest will spawn as regular villagers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Meet the Blacksmith&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/SYcGsN9.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/tTMEaz6.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/HioTyym.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(File type is yet to be decided) Just like with the stylist, the quantity of files will determine the content the blacksmith has for you to trade.
He has two different shapes, and it will grow bigger if there are more files of its kind.
He can craft all kinds of weapons and armor, and will be able to upgrade your current gear at a reasonable price!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week we will introduce new characters and there will be more news about development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we announced that the first public version of the game would be available in spring but it will have to wait to see the light until summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more &lt;a href=&quot;http://adventuros.evelend.com/blog/9&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;A delayed game is eventually good, but a rushed game is forever bad&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
- Shigeru Miyamoto&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-06-13T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/06/13/development-update-8.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/06/13/development-update-8.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #7</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;To our dearest Adventurers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/UR416V4.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/N91iLmw.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/YuPr2FD.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Q8gHtSZ.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since the last update. AdventurOS is looking great, and it can start to be considered ready for Early Access release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, our schedule has suffered changes due to bureaucratic reasons. If you still wonder what exactly happened, Lorena has got a pretty accurate &lt;a style=&quot;color: #6893BD;; font-weight: bold;&quot; href=&quot;http://lorena.evelend.com/indie-heaven-and-hell/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;description for you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are very close to fixing the whole thing, and, believe us, we are so looking forward to it! We apologize and would like to thank you all for your kind words of support and for always being there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good stuff is so close!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-06-07T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/06/07/development-update-7.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/06/07/development-update-7.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Development Update #6</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/OhFra7K.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;float:right;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Evelend we continue working hard in order to get all the basic features ready for the next release, and then we will be almost set to launch the early access version of AdventurOS, specially focusing on a mod-friendly environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a some new tools which will make easier the development and mod creation. For instance, a fully functional level editor will be available giving the user a good way to create cohesive and fun to play levels for the directory interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Cbkd3cA.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve redesigned the main menu, the intro and we have gone deeper into the main quest of the adventure mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll be satisfied only when we feel that what we have in our hands  is a functional and interesting first product before releasing the early-access, containing a logical amount of playability and testing for the betterment of next releases, and of course including all the modding tools we are developing so far and a user friendly guide on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your patience!
&lt;br /&gt;We love you all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-05-12T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/05/12/development-update-6.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/05/12/development-update-6.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>We are getting there!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/BnRt4Ks.png&quot; style=&quot;background:white;max-width: 600px;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Adventurers,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have exciting news! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working really hard to include all the basic features we can into the next Alpha version of the promising AdventurOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it looks like this will be the last Alpha release, smoothing the way for quality Beta times. On time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is wonderful to watch all of AdventurOS pieces starting to fit together, we are really looking forward to the testing and feedback from the Steam community, so the spring release we promised is very, very likely to be fulfilled in no time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, please feel free to get in touch with your impressions, questions or suggestions, and remember it was you guys who made this possible and we could not be more grateful for this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks and keep enjoying, we love you all!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-04-15T00:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/04/15/we-are-getting-there.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/04/15/we-are-getting-there.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>AdventurOS 0.0.8 coming soon!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Adventurers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the highlights of the last development weeks: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xKlGH6w.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are introducing an easy to use menu that will contain all the information you need to keep track of your location, inventory, stats and skills. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The castle’s map is being developed and will be displayed on a unique way so you can know where you are and where you have already been. You will be able to set a waypoint to a folder you already visited so you can travel without checking on the map. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inventory is divided in different subsections so it’s always organized and tidy. Items can be acquired by killing monsters and/or found inside chests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/W1V8Mq8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/dfj0K7V.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new level generator is on its way to arrive to AdventurOS alpha. Rooms will be generated differently and there will be 3 main layouts: big rooms, corridors and towers. Mixing these 3 different kinds of level generators, the game will give a similar experience to a Castlevania map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing the level generator and the menu we will be working on adding items, monsters, and environments to the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the next Alpha build you will be able to experience the full power of the AdventurOS inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your feedback and bug reports! We are getting very close to the point where Alpha becomes Beta!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-03-11T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/03/11/adventuros-008-coming-soon.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/03/11/adventuros-008-coming-soon.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Fan Art Contest. Get your AdventurOS Alpha access!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;To all Gnududes of the real:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/KCjATB8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big chance is knocking at your door!

&lt;p&gt;We have recently got big amounts of messages requesting a chance to make a donation in exchange for the alpha access purchased by our Indiegogo backers.
Please, understand that with their contribution they did not only buy an access, but vouched for us while still at an early stage, so their rewards for their trust and belief must be kept exclusive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the team faces a low demographic rate of Gnududes (Linux users, that is), and all kind members of the AdventurOS family are up to making room for some of you guys!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to be one of our Linux testers, submit your Fan Art piece to Twitter with the hashtag #adventurosfanart before March 10th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 10th two winners will get the Alpha access right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/HOqJw61.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the growing AdventurOS family! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-02-25T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/02/25/fan-art-contest-get-your-adventuros-alpha-access.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/02/25/fan-art-contest-get-your-adventuros-alpha-access.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Tell us the story! (Teaser)</title>
          <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/lon83aO1cVU?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello dear Adventurers! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development goes great and we are ready to proudly announce this is the last countdown for the awesome AdventurOS Beta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you enjoy our latest available teaser! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, thank you all soo much for your feedback and support!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-02-07T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/02/07/tell-us-the-story-teaser.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/02/07/tell-us-the-story-teaser.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>AdventurOS 0.0.05: Development Update #5</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/dXjykBO.gif&quot; style=&quot;float:right;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working hard on the awesome AdventurOS, which keeps progressively evolving and getting closer and closer to its Beta stage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(If you are part of the alpha team get your new version here: &lt;a href=&quot;/alpha&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://adventuros.evelend.com/alpha/&lt;/a&gt; ) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alpha access is a reward for all those who have believed in our project since the very beginning and supported us with significant contributions. However, we have got such a big wave of newcomers offering their collaboration that we are considering a contest where some more alpha accesses can be obtained. Stay tuned! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on and until the auto-updater is ready, we will release updates every other week, so there is more content in each of them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This update includes a brand new concept regarding monsters, being their size based on the length of the file name and their color based on the first character of it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/OWf16c4.png&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/rMgpmJL.png&quot; style=&quot;width:100%;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much more content that you can check at the changelog. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are especially happy to be finally presenting you the first version that works for Linux, after struggling to get through numerous compatibility issues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/forum&quot;&gt;The online community&lt;/a&gt; keeps evolving too. Bugs are reported through it and it is becoming more and more user friendly. Join us, play, subscribe, contribute, enjoy! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-01-28T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/01/28/adventuros-0005-development-update-5.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/01/28/adventuros-0005-development-update-5.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Alpha Release: Development Update #4</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello dear Adventurers! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The holidays are finally over and we want to celebrate it with a new update. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On AdventurOS 0.0.04 you will find a new monster as well as improved settings in order to create them, including the addition of extension filter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/TG5tSvI.gif&quot; style=&quot;float:left;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The indexer has been optimized and there have been several launcher adjustments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, there have been many changes made on the fight engine, stamina has been rebalanced and now the game counts on new HP and MP orbs to recover health and mana. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cleared up levels are set to be remembered during session and there are breakable objects now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will find all these and many more, enjoy and stay tuned for the next update! &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          <pubDate>2014-01-07T00:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
          <link>http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/01/07/alpha-release-development-update-4.html</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">http://adventuros.evelend.com/2014/01/07/alpha-release-development-update-4.html</guid>
        </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>